

Taiwan

github.com/ambientlight

tarasvozniuk.com

stackoverflow.com/users/2380455

in linkedin.com/in/tarasvozniuk/

## **SUMMARY**

Lead developer at GeoThings with broad expertise including mobile development, full-stack, cloud architecture, devops as well as deep learning. To some degree my work involved jumping across stacks with quick iterations towards sensible solutions, the kind of dynamism we often experience in startup world. My free time is largely spend tinkering with experimental stacks, most recently with CRDTs and distributed systems using them. My ideas and open source contribution gravitated towards better developer tooling.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Lead Developer, Software Architect | GeoThings | Taiwan | 2017 - Present

- \* setted up and maintained OSM server infrastructure: tilezen stack, osm overpass
- \* redesigned and performed incremental rewrite of our old frontend angularjs codebase to angular4. Built GIS functionality on top of mapbox-gl.
- \* designed and built a scalable cloud infrastructure for our service on AWS utilizing lambdas & ECS behind ALB, aurora postgres, redis, S3 behind CloudFront CDN.
- \* built machine learning pipeline capable of extracting roadside objects with its locations from windshield cam videos utilizing YoloV3 / deep-sort.
- \* responsible for all our infrastructure operations,
- \* provided almost 24x7 response rate (vocations included) for critical fixes and infrastructure issues.
- \* responsible for stack decisions for all our services and projects
- \* helped our team to embrace and adopt new stacks, functional and reactive paradigms, provided guidances to our interns, conducted interview

#### iOS Developer | GeoThings | Taiwan | Sept 2015 - 2017

- \* developed map-centric application on top of WhirlyGlobe-Maply and later MapboxGL
- st rewrote a legacy objective-c survey collection app in Swift
- \* wrote few server-side swift components and crawlers (PerfectSwift)
- \* introduced redux and its single-store concepts into our app with ReSwift, subsequently ported ReSwift to android as ReKotlin.

# iOS Developer | Sixnology | Taiwan | Apr 2013 - Aug 2014

Built DLNA-complient audio streaming player for iOS supporting media from local library, UPNP Media Servers, and Spotify.

# **EDUCATION**

#### B.S. Computer Science, B.S. Finance & IM | National Chaio Tung University | earned Jun. 2015

Fortunate to come and study in Taiwan, I have to give great credit to NCTU for who I became. Development career was my ultimate goal, but as I was also curious to explore stock trading, I decided to get a double degree.

#### **RECOGNITIONS**

### Best Potential Team Award - Beyond Future Mobility: MIT Media Lab X NCTU

Our team built a personal flying assistant that is safe to operate in indoor environment: helium-powered drone(airship) with arduino which communicates with iOS app via bluetooth. IOS app is used as a remote which can also send the accelerometer and bearing data to allow drone to follow the person with the phone.

# **LANGUAGES**

Typescript, Javascript, ReasonML, Python, Swift, Java, Kotlin, Ocaml, Objective-C, C, C++

## **STACKS**

react, angular, react-native, electron, django, aws amplify, serverless, aws lambda, cloudformation, docker, aws ecs, kubernetes, postgresql, dynamodb, sqlite, neo4j, redis, realm, redux, rxjs, graphql, logux, pixijs, jest, selenium, webpack, fastlane, bitrise, githubactions, keras tensorflow, opencv

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

ReKotlin, AWS Amplify, tilequeue, reductive-dev-tools, reductive-observable, amplify-cli-action, bs-rx, GithubIssuesExtension